[♪♪♪]
[wind blasting]
[all crying out]
[shouting] Whoa!
[grunting with effort]
[shouting]
These unnatural winds
defy all logic!
[all shouting] Whoa!
[grunting and grumbling]
[shrieking roar]
I can't leave you all alone
for a minute!
[happy grunting]
[♪♪♪]
[grunting with impact]
Whoa!
Wyldfyre!
I have never been more excited
to see you.
Arin?
Why are you here?
I thought you peaced out.
[Arin] I'm trying
not to let the world end.
Well, I'm here now,
so it won't.
[grunting with effort]
Oof!
[♪♪♪]
[revving]
[Riyu shrieking]
[grunting with impact]
Riyu!
[groaning softly]
[grunting with effort]
You okay, boy?
[grumbling softly]
[wheezing]
That thing is way cool!
Can I try?
It won't look as cool on you.
Hurtful.
We have more pressing problems,
you two.
Anyone see
where the Forbidden Five went?
I...
I had the last two blades.
I know I should have just
flown off with them,
but I tried to save Ras,
then Rox attacked me.
Hold on.
If the Five have
all the blades,
doesn't that mean
they can free--
[deep rumbling,
all yelping in alarm]
-[heavy slamming]
-[gasping in shock]
[together] Thunderfang!
[snarling]
[deafening roar]
♪ Lost in the unknown ♪
♪ Together we will rise ♪
♪ We fight ♪
♪ Be a ninja for what's right ♪
[thunderclap]
[deafening roar]
I knew he was big.
Yeah, but that is like big-big.
[wind gusting]
Be safe, Ninja.
Cole...
I think the MergeQuakes
are back.
No, this is
something different.
We better
gather up the Finders.
My documents!
This weather is unauthorized!
[Thunderfang] Source Dragons!
You will rue the day
you rejected me!
Where'd the Forbidden Five go?
Maybe Thunderfang ate 'em.
Would explain why
he's in such a foul mood.
You know, 'cause they're
probably hard to digest?
Make you sick, and--
I got it.
You didn't laugh.
I reacted correctly.
[deafening roar]
I have no idea
how we beat this thing,
except there's one of him
and ten of us,
so let's come at him
from all sides!
[Wyldfyre] Works for me!
Ninja... go!
[♪♪♪]
[roaring]
[gasping and screaming]
[grunting with impact]
[Thunderfang] Last time,
it took an Arc Dragon of Focus
to defeat me!
You puny mortals have no chance!
[yelping]
[grunting with impact]
Much appreciated.
Ooh!
H'yah!
[earthquake rumbling]
Ah!
You ugly jerks are an insult
to dragons everywhere!
[engine revving]
[grunting with effort]
[snarling]
[gasping in fright]
H'ah!
[grumbling]
Like that? Have some more!
[roaring]
[yelping and groaning]
[gasping]
[stomping]
[Frak] Thanks, man.
[Arin]
Couldn't let you get hurt
on our first
Ninja adventure together!
[gasping]
[roaring]
There you are.
Ras! Look out!
[grunting with effort]
H'yah!
[Arin] Leave him alone!
Aah!
[grunting in pain]
[snarling]
[gasping in fright]
[grunting with effort]
[roaring]
[Riyu screeching]
[circuits shorting]
[Wyldfyre] Can't you
do anything without my help?
Hi'yah!
-[Thunderfang roaring]
-Whoo!
That was satisfying.
[circuits shorting]
Whoa!
[gasping]
[♪♪♪]
[Thunderfang gasping]
[deafening roar]
[wind gusting]
[Thunderfang] I smell the power
of a Source Dragon Conduit!
A direct line to
the Source Dragons themselves?
-You!
-[Lloyd gasping]
Draining a Conduit's power
will be transcendent!
Whose energy do you channel?
Motion?
That incessant busybody?
Or the self-obsessed Strength?
[slamming dirt, claw dragging]
[Lloyd grunting with effort]
[Thunderfang] Or is it Life?
[roaring]
[Lloyd gasping wearily]
[Thunderfang]
How ironic would that be?
[Lloyd yelping]
[groaning with impact]
[inhaling]
[Thunderfang yelps in pain]
[squawking]
You need to shelter
from this natural disaster, sir.
There's nothing natural
about this.
[wind gusting]
[squawking]
I've got you, Fritz!
H'yah!
[grunting with effort]
On your feet
if you want to survive!
[grunting with effort]
Huah!
[Nya] Not bad
for some rando mercenary.
Aren't you supposed
to be unstoppable?
[roaring]
Aah!
I knew I should never fly
not on a dragon!
-Aah!
-Wyldfyre!
[yelping]
[grunting with impact]
-[groaning]
-You hurt?
No way, I don't get hurt.
[wincing groan]
Hey, I gave it some thought.
You would look really cool
in that mech.
Seriously?
You're thinking about that now?
Really cool!
You're right,
this is pretty cool.
H'yah!
[grunting with effort]
[stone crumbling]
[♪♪♪]
Couldn't let you get hurt
on our first
Ninja adventure together.
High velocity contact
at the anterior
may yield results.
Acknowledged!
[roaring]
[Thunderfang] Pests!
[grunting with impact]
[engine revving]
[foot stomping]
[grunting with impact]
[roaring]
[Thunderfang] Conduit!
[snarling]
Oh, come on!
This is a loaner!
Now you just
scratched it all up!
[yelping]
[grunting with impact]
[grunting with effort]
Ah!
[energy crackling]
No way...
[♪♪♪]
Thought I'd...
lightning up the mood!
And terrible puns?
[worried grunting]
[shrieking]
[stomping footsteps]
[Thunderfang] Conduit!
[Lloyd screaming]
[gasping in horror]
Lloyd! Lloyd!
[gasping]
Unh!
[screaming] No!
[evil cackling]
[Arin yelping]
[screaming]
[powerful roaring]
No!
[grunting with effort]
[♪♪♪]
Lloyd! Lloyd! Come on!
No!
[roaring]
[screaming]
[Thunderfang] Source Dragons!
I have reaped the soul
of one of your mortal Conduits!
You can deny me no longer!
I know you hear me,
and I will not stop
until I devour
all of your souls as well!
Souls?
[gasping]
[Arin] What is this stuff?
[departed soul] Don't ask me.
Drinking it is what helps souls
move on.
"Helps souls move on..."
[grunting with effort]
[gasping]
[Ras] Don't be a fool.
A moving target
through the winds of chaos?
You don't have enough anger
for that kind of strength.
The Arin I know,
my best friend,
his strength comes
from his kindness,
his generosity,
his hope.
[Arin] You're right.
I don't have enough anger
to pull this off...
[♪♪♪]
I have something better.
Ninja...
Go!
[♪♪♪]
[Thunderfang] What?!
[snarling]
[♪♪♪]
[grunting with effort]
[Riyu groaning]
This is weird, right?
Arin threw something at him.
[grunting]
[roaring]
[Thunderfang] Impossible...
[crumbling]
[♪♪♪]
[bursting]
[crying out]
[gasping]
[breathing hard]
Lloyd!
[gasping]
[storm dissipating]
I've had
some really weird days,
but this might be
the weirdest one yet.
[all laughing]
Oh...
[Riyu grunting happily]
[grumbling]
[♪♪♪]
Thank you, Wyldfyre,
and I'm sure
some of the other Ninja helped.
We are so sorry
for our actions.
We know
you weren't yourselves, Tyr.
We owe you Ninja our freedom.
It was really Arin
who freed you.
[Tyr] Then you are
a great hero, Arin.
Oh!
Well, not really.
I was the reason
the Five freed Thunderfang
to begin with,
and fighting him
was a group effort, and he--
--Is a great hero.
[Ras] Arin...
Time to go.
[Riyu growling]
I'm sorry, everyone.
My parents...
[Kai] What?
No...
Arin, you know better.
Lloyd?
I'm sorry too.
What the heck
is going on here?
Arin, wait!
You're coming with us?
Together forever, right?
And why should I allow you
to travel in my company?
You don't think
having the Elemental Master
of Technology
will help us on our mission?
[grumbling]
You don't have to do this.
Of course I do.
Who else is gonna
watch out for you?
Are you seriously going to
let Ras leave with them?
They're free to make
their own decisions.
That's the difference
between us and Ras.
And you're not worried
about them?
I didn't say that.
[groaning sadly]
There!
[grunting with effort]
[groaning]
Ah!
You need a splint on that leg.
Let's get you
back to the Monastery.
Why are you gonna help me?
I know who you are,
you big dummy.
Uh, yeah,
a secret man of mystery
whose identity will never--
Elemental Lightning?
Really?
So?
Lots of people probably have
Elemental Lightning.
-Nope.
-[groaning]
[together] Jay?
Don't pretend you know me!
And I'm not going
to your stupid Monastery!
Normal people don't just
have monasteries!
It's weird!
And another thing--
Ow! Owie-ow-ow-ow-ow! [sobs]
Get me to your Monastery!
Can't you see I need help?
[♪♪♪]
Congratulations, Ninja!
You did it!
I guess,
but this win doesn't exactly
feel like a win.
Well, our guests
would disagree.
Guests?
Lobbo-lobbo crushes
pie-eating record!
[all cheering]
[cheering and celebrating]
[crowd chanting]
Lobbo! Lobbo! Lobbo!
[♪♪♪]
Wyldfyre!
I knew you'd save us!
Rawr...
Rawr!
[snarling playfully]
Mr. Frohicky makes great pizza!
Without flies, even!
Whoa. Jay?
[wincing] Ah!
I can't believe it!
Bring it in!
Get away, weirdo.
Still no memory?
I got plenty of memories, bub.
Just none of them are of you.
Wow. Okay...
[groaning]
[laughing and celebrating]
And still no Arin?
He and Sora went with Ras.
Arin thinks Ras
can bring his parents
back from the dead.
Dead?
[scoffing] I know for a fact
that Arin kid's parents
are alive.
What?
Hello? I worked
for the Administration.
Head of the Department
of Realm Reassignment?
What do you think I did there?
I know exactly where
Arin's parents
were reassigned,
and it's really, really weird.
[bucket rattling in the wind]
Dearly Departed,
this may come as a shock,
but you have transitioned
out of the living world.
I vow to protect you
as you move into...
Okay, wow.
You're a big one.
[distant screeching]
[snarling]
Stay back.
I'll ward them off.
[barking and snarling]
[Thunderfang]
I can handle myself.
[snarling]
What?
That's impossible.
[Thunderfang] In the afterlife,
anything is possible.
[screaming]
[evil cackling]
[maniacal laughter]
[♪♪♪]